<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Ledger</title>
    <description>Tutorials and documentation for my projects
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 15:49:19 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 15:49:19 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacking Cancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Guppster/HackingCancer&quot;&gt;HackingCancer&lt;/a&gt; is an attempt to
create a challenging web applet game in Java with the main purpose of utilizing
the power of crowdsourcing to improve cancer research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a Side-Scroller, platformer game in which the user first creates their
own map from visual representations of a Gene MicroArray. The user is
challenged to determine the path with the most amount of orbs present which
would allow them to collect these orbs in the second stage of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This path is a unautomatable process due to sher amount of data and thus is the
bottleneck for scientists in their progression to find a cure for cancer.
Allowing users to solve these simple problems has been statistically proven to
increase analysis speed by 600% (Jonna Reynolds, Cancer Research UK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the map has been created, the user is placed at the starting point on
their own map. The map is populated with many monsters that will kill the user
if they touch them to make the game challenging and competitive. Upon reaching
the finish line the user is shown their score and the score + the extracted
research data is saved online in JSON format for further analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner, Konrad Pfundner, and I programmed this project in under 36 hours 
at HackWestern 2015 and recieved and were awarded as one of the top finalist
at the event.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further analysis take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Guppster/HackingCancer&quot;&gt;code on
Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 15:25:48 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/hacking-cancer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/hacking-cancer.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Java 8 is INSANE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone who has programmed with me knows I really enjoy writing Java. It might
be because it was the first “real” programming language I learned back in highschool 
or because iv memorized so much of it. Regardless of that though, the additions 
featured in Java 8 have greatly evolved the language and transformed it into 
something completely new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently a had been getting bored of using Java at my job and started to push to
write tools in a different language, but now that iv discovered Java 8 streams,
lamba expressions, and more I can’t wait to use more Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I will discuss some features of JDK8 and show examples of how to use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of things added&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lamda Expressions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes to Generic Types&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stream Collections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Functional Interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small changes to Reflection and Annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:24:30 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/java-8-is-insane.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/java-8-is-insane.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simplicity of a Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to make a blog for some time now but always decided not to because I couldn’t
find a simple, efficient, and productive technology stack to support it. I looked into the 
usual: medium, wordpress, wix, etc and found them all to be too heavy weight for my application.
What I really wanted was a simple blog with no comments, no share buttons, no special formatting.
Just text and images with no distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One online blogging system I really like is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. I think Medium has really eye catching blog posts
due to the way the words are placed and the fonts that are used. I think these features have greatly 
contributed to the success of Medium in the past few years. The style of my blog is very similar to 
Medium, except it doesnt have any extra social media style functions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 19:04:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/simplicity-of-a-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/simplicity-of-a-blog.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HackPrinceton 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I visited Princeton campus to attend HackPrinceton, a hackathon hosted by the university.
Out of the 10+ hackathons iv went to I feel this was one of the best hackathon experiences iv had. 
Everything from the sleeping arrangements to the overall structure and layout of the hackathon felt well organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;558&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/resize_Princeton-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended this hackathon with two of my coworkers and one new friend I met at Princeton. We spent a week trying to
come up with ideas before the hackathon began and ultimatly settled on creating the “Photo-Orb”. This would be a device
capable of circling a human or an object and taking a 360 degree portrait of it. All 360 cameras take an outward facing 
image so we wanted to make an inward facing solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were three components to this project: assembling the hardware, programming the hardware,
and programming a webpage to take many images and stitch them together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my web skills arn’t as strong as my teammates and they hadn’t worked with hardware very much, I decided to 
help with creating the device. We planned to make it a RC car with a selfie stickt attached to the top so it could 
drive around the individual while taking pictures with the phone attached to it. We quickly assembled the RC car 
without any problems using two DC motors and some wheels. We used a H-bridge to control the direction the motors 
were spinning. Using DC motors with an H-bridge created lots of problems for us later on because we weren’t able 
to accurately control the vehicle’s position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;810&quot; height=&quot;770&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rsz_princeton-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My teammate and I wrote some python code to prototype a movement scheme where we would run one motor longer than 
the other to turn in a circle. It worked! We got excited and wanted to solder it together to create moving vehicle 
but our limited soldering experience created lots of problems as well. Many of our connections weren’t as solid as 
we needed them to be for a moving vehicle. Sometimes a random motor would stop running, or would spin in random 
directions. We spent many hours following the wiring connections and cleaning up the soldering but then realized 
it was a bug in the code controlling the H-bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;810&quot; height=&quot;910&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rsz_princeton-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we finished fixed the bug and the other half of the team finished the website / camera part and everything
was ready for demoing. We impressed many judges and were awarded with Nvidia Shield mobile gaming consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the project, I spent a lot of time playing around with a 3D printer and exploring the beautiful campus.
Some things I printed out were: a Jeep logo, a Pontiac logo, a coin with the Bitcoin logo on it and the totem from the movie
Inception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/Princeton-4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 18:32:03 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2017/04/06/hackprinceton-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/2017/04/06/hackprinceton-2017.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
