<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Ledger</title>
    <description>Tutorials and documentation for my projects
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 22:00:38 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 22:00:38 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Coding a Cloud Drive</title>
        <description>&lt;h1 id=&quot;hooli-drive&quot;&gt;Hooli Drive&lt;/h1&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Guppster/Drive&quot;&gt;Hooli Drive&lt;/a&gt; is my client and server
implementation of a personal cloud storage service (sometimes referred to as
an online backup service) that can be used for file sharing and collaboration.
This project was programmed in C and was my first exposure to memory leaks and
other complex C problems as well as the &lt;a href=&quot;https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/OSI_model&quot;&gt;OSI network
stack&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-the-tool&quot;&gt;About the tool&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;When the server and client programs are run simultaneously the client’s
specified directory will be synced with the same directory on the server. This
means any files in the client directory that do not already exist or are
outdated on the server, will be replaced. The process starts with the HMDS
(Hooli MetaData Server) sending filenames and checksums of those files to the
server, then the server compares that data with it’s directory. The server
sends back a request specifying the files that need to be replaced and then
those files are transmitted in blocks and reconstructed on the server side.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The filenames and checksums are sent using TCP within HMDS because this data
needs reliable data transfer and is not expected to be large. The file data
itself is sent using protocol i designed on top of UDP which ensures reliable
data transfer while taking advantage of the speed benefit of UDP.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;about-development&quot;&gt;About Development&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is one of my favourite personal projects because I love learning about
networking and low level C programming. I got a chance to experiment with the
different layers of networking using hands-on programming.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I began working on this project while reading the textbook ‘Networking. A
top-down approach’ to better understand UDP and TCP.  I used both these
protocols and learned when they are applicable and how i can leverage their
strengths.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Development of this project was done on a virtual environment generated by
&lt;a href=&quot;https://www.vagrantup.com/&quot;&gt;Vagrant&lt;/a&gt;. This turned out to be a great decision
when I had to switch development environments because it allowed me to continue
programming without any problems. I plan to continue using Vagrant in my future
projects and maybe experiment with Docker.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Overall this was a very good learning experience for me and I will continue
seeking for more difficult adventures like this one.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 21:19:41 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/coding-a-cloud-drive.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/coding-a-cloud-drive.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>You Mouse You Lose!</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;For the past year iv been productivly using my computer without touching my
mouse for many hours at a time.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 16:52:29 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/you-mouse-you-lose.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/you-mouse-you-lose.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Programming Style Guide</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyday I run into poorly written code and spend lots of my time reformatting
it; therefore, i’m creating this style guide as something i can quickly
reference when starting a project with a new team. Follow this guide, and
everything will be great. Some things in this guide will be only applicable to
java but most points will work in the majority of languages.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;spacing&quot;&gt;Spacing&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Your lines of code should be adiqutely spaced out. Only lines that are directly
related to eachother should be touching eachother.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 16:38:53 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/programming-style-guide.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/programming-style-guide.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Hacking Cancer</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Guppster/HackingCancer&quot;&gt;HackingCancer&lt;/a&gt; is an attempt to 
create a challenging web applet game in Java with the main purpose of utilizing
the power of crowd sourcing to improve cancer research.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;98&quot; height=&quot;50&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/hackingcancer.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is a side-scroller, platform game in which the user first creates their
own map from visual representations of a Gene Micro-Array. The user is
challenged to determine the path with the most amount of orbs present which
would allow them to collect these orbs in the second stage of the game.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This path is not an automatable process due to the sheer amount of data and
thus is the bottleneck for scientists in their progression to find a cure for
cancer.  Allowing users to solve these simple problems has been statistically
proven to increase analysis speed by 600% (Jonna Reynolds, Cancer Research UK).&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Once the map has been created, the user is placed at the starting point on
their own map. The map is populated with many monsters that will kill the user
if they touch them to make the game challenging and competitive. Upon reaching
the finish line the user is shown their score and the score + the extracted
research data is saved online in JSON format for further analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My partner, Konrad Pfundner, and I programmed this project in under 36 hours at
HackWestern 2015 and were awarded as one of the top finalist at the event. Our
goal for this hackathon was to attempt something challenging and really improve
our programming skills. To achieve this level of difficulty we refrained from
using any external libraries or frameworks to make the game development easier
and programmed everything using basic java graphics and processing. This
decision turned out to be very rewarding as I ended up learning a lot about
drawing and manipulating shapes in java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;HackWestern 2015 was also my first time presenting a hackathon project on stage
by myself. I had been awake for 36 hours and didn’t have any time to prepare so
it was quite an interesting experience. I was quite surprised that we made it
to the finals because we spent the first night of the hackathon trying to hack
the internal display system of a Tesla… that was fun, but didn’t work out
very well.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;While thinking of ideas we were trying to make something that would cause a
social impact because that was one of the sponsor prizes and we like to win.
We ended up qualifying for the following list of prizes on
&lt;a href=&quot;https://hackwestern.devpost.com/submissions/35020-hackingcancer&quot;&gt;DevPost&lt;/a&gt;:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Most Creative App&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best Use of Mashape APIs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best Use of AI&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best Domain Name Registered&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Best Social Impact Hack&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;For further analysis take a look at the &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Guppster/HackingCancer&quot;&gt;code on
Github&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Fri, 07 Apr 2017 15:25:48 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/hacking-cancer.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/07/hacking-cancer.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Java 8 is INSANE</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;Everyone who has programmed with me knows I really enjoy writing Java. It might
be because it was the first “real” programming language I learned back in highschool 
or because iv memorized so much of it. Regardless of that though, the additions 
featured in Java 8 have greatly evolved the language and transformed it into 
something completely new!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Recently a had been getting bored of using Java at my job and started to push to
write tools in a different language, but now that iv discovered Java 8 streams,
lambda expressions, and more I can’t wait to use more Java.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In this post I will discuss some features of JDK8 and show examples of how to use them.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here is a list of things added&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Lambda Expressions&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Changes to Generic Types&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Stream Collections&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Functional Interfaces&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Small changes to Reflection and Annotations&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 20:24:30 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/java-8-is-insane.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/java-8-is-insane.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simplicity of a Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to make a blog for some time now but always decided not to
because I couldn’t find a simple, efficient, and productive technology stack to
support it. I looked into the usual: medium, wordpress, wix, etc and found them
all to be too heavy weight for my application.  What I really wanted was a
simple blog with no comments, no share buttons, no special formatting.  Just
text and images with no distractions. I needed to create an emersive environment 
for my reader.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;One online blogging system I really like is &lt;a href=&quot;http://www.medium.com&quot;&gt;Medium&lt;/a&gt;. I
think Medium has really eye catching blog posts due to the way the words are
placed and the fonts that are used. I think these features have greatly
contributed to the success of Medium in the past few years. The style of my
blog is very similar to Medium, except it doesn’t have any extra social media
style functions.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A major goal I set for this blog was to minimize the amount of non-content
related links on the page. I use vim bindings in my browser to navigate
webpages instead of using the mouse so when a page has too many links it
becomes really annoying to use.  On this blog if you try exposing the links,
there will be very few that are not directly related to the article. This keeps
vim linking very simple and easy to follow.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1022&quot; height=&quot;217&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/medium.png&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Personally, I am very easily distracted, so when reading a blog post with many
other elements on the sides I find it hard to focus and absorb the content i’m reading.
For example above you can see one of Medium’s mistakes. When you are reading an 
article on medium there will always be this floating  social media sharing column. I don’t
think readers need rapid fire access to share an article.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 19:04:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/simplicity-of-a-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/simplicity-of-a-blog.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HackPrinceton 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I visited Princeton campus to attend HackPrinceton, a hackathon hosted by the university.
Out of the 10+ hackathons iv went to I feel this was one of the best hackathon experiences iv had. 
Everything from the sleeping arrangements to the overall structure and layout of the hackathon felt well organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1000&quot; height=&quot;558&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/resize_Princeton-2.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended this hackathon with two of my coworkers and one new friend I met at Princeton. We spent a week trying to
come up with ideas before the hackathon began and ultimately settled on creating the “Photo-Orb”. This would be a device
capable of circling a human or an object and taking a 360-degree portrait of it. All 360 cameras take an outward facing
image so we wanted to make an inward facing solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were three components to this project: assembling the hardware, programming the hardware,
and programming a web page to take many images and stitch them together.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Since my web skills are not as strong as my teammates and they hadn’t worked with hardware very much, I decided to
help with creating the device. We planned to make it an RC car with a selfie stick attached to the top so it could
drive around the individual while taking pictures with the phone attached to it. We quickly assembled the RC car
without any problems using two DC motors and some wheels. We used a H-bridge to control the direction the motors
were spinning. Using DC motors with an H-bridge created lots of problems for us later on because we weren’t able to accurately control the vehicle’s position.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;810&quot; height=&quot;770&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rsz_princeton-1.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My teammate and I wrote some python code to prototype a movement scheme where we would run one motor longer than the other to turn in a circle. It worked! We got excited and wanted to solder it together to create moving vehicle but our limited soldering experience created lots of problems as well. Many of our connections weren’t as solid as we needed them to be for a moving vehicle. Sometimes a random motor would stop running or would spin in random directions. We spent many hours following the wiring connections and cleaning up the soldering but then realized it was a bug in the code controlling the H-bridge.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;810&quot; height=&quot;910&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/rsz_princeton-3.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Ultimately we finished fixed the bug and the other half of the team finished the website/camera part and everything
was ready for demoing. We impressed many judges and were awarded Nvidia Shield mobile gaming consoles.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Other than the project, I spent a lot of time playing around with a 3D printer and exploring the beautiful campus.
Some things I printed out were: a Jeep logo, a Pontiac logo, a coin with the Bitcoin logo on it and the totem from the movie
Inception.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;amp-img width=&quot;1080&quot; height=&quot;736&quot; layout=&quot;responsive&quot; src=&quot;/assets/images/Princeton-4.jpg&quot;&gt;&lt;/amp-img&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 18:32:03 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/tech/2017/04/06/hackprinceton-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/tech/2017/04/06/hackprinceton-2017.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>tech</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
