<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Project Ledger</title>
    <description>Tutorials and documentation for my projects
</description>
    <link>http://localhost:4000/</link>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/>
    <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 19:15:16 -0400</pubDate>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 19:15:16 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <generator>Jekyll v3.3.1</generator>
    
      <item>
        <title>Simplicity of a Blog</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;I have wanted to make a blog for some time now but always decided not to because I couldn’t
find a simple, efficient, and productive technology stack to support it. I looked into the 
usual: medium, wordpress, wix, etc and found them all to be too heavy weight for my application.
What I really wanted was a simple blog with no comments, no share buttons, no special formatting.
Just text and images with no distractions.&lt;/p&gt;

</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 19:04:25 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/simplicity-of-a-blog.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/2017/04/06/simplicity-of-a-blog.html</guid>
        
        
      </item>
    
      <item>
        <title>HackPrinceton 2017</title>
        <description>&lt;p&gt;This past weekend I visited Princeton campus to attend HackPrinceton, a hackathon hosted by the university.
Out of the 10+ hackathons iv went to I feel this was one of the best hackathon experiences iv had. 
Everything from the sleeping arrangements to the overall structure and layout of the hackathon felt well organized.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I attended this hackathon with two of my coworkers and one new friend I met at Princeton. We spent a week trying to
come up with ideas before the hackathon began and ultimatly settled on creating the “Photo-Orb”. This would be a device
capable of circling a human or an object and taking a 360 degree portrait of it. All 360 cameras take an outward facing 
image so we wanted to make an inward facing solution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;There were three components to this project: assembling the hardware, programming the hardware,
and programming a webpage to take many images and stitch them together.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
        <pubDate>Thu, 06 Apr 2017 18:32:03 -0400</pubDate>
        <link>http://localhost:4000/hackathon/programming/2017/04/06/hackprinceton-2017.html</link>
        <guid isPermaLink="true">http://localhost:4000/hackathon/programming/2017/04/06/hackprinceton-2017.html</guid>
        
        
        <category>hackathon</category>
        
        <category>programming</category>
        
      </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
